Guide to the Little Square Review Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Little Square Review Records
1960-2000
YCAL MSS 711
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.25
(6 boxes)
The Little Square Review Records contain correspondence, printed material, production files, a photograph reproduction, proofs, and business papers relating to the production and publication of journal issues.
Little Square Review
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Ralph B. Sipper, Bookseller on the Sinclair Lewis Fund, 2000. Gift of John Ridland, 2000-2005.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Little Square Review
The Little Square Review, edited by poet John Ridland, was published from 1966 to 1972. Each issue of The Little Square Review was devoted to the work of one or two poets that Ridland considered to have not received sufficient recognition in larger publications. Ten issues were released during its existence.
Scope and Contents
The Little Square Review Records contain correspondence, printed material, production files, a photograph reproduction, proofs, and business papers relating to the production and publication of journal issues.
Arrangement
Organized into three groupings: I. April 2000 Acquisition, 1960-2000. II. April 2003 Acquisition, 1974. III. August 2005 Acquisition, undated.
Little Square Review; American poetry -- United States -- 20th Century; Little magazines -- United States; Poets, American -- 20th Century; Editors -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Ridland, John, 1933-
- April 2000 Acquisition, 1960-2000, undated; 1; 3.21; (4 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into three series: Office Files, Correspondence, and Printed Material.
  Scope and Contents
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 28
  Contains correspondence, printed material, production files, proofs and business papers relating to the production of each issue.
  - Office files
    - Payments, 1966-1969 (Box 1)
    - Orders, 1968-1969; 2 (Box 1)
    - Distribution, 1966-1973 (Box 1)
    - Rejections A-G, 1967-1973 (Box 1)
    - Rejections H-Q, 1967-1973 (Box 1)
    - Rejections R-Z, 1967-1973 (Box 1)
    - Ledger books, 1966-1974; 2 (Box 1)
    - Little Square Review #1, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Little Square Review #1. Walter Clark, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Little Square Review #1,# 2, #3 and #4. Responses, 1966-1969 (Box 1)
    - Little Square Review #2. Robert Peters, 1966-1967; 3 (Box 1)
    - Little Square Review #3. Ed Fussell, 1967-1973; 2 (Box 1)
    - Little Square Review #4
      - Barry Spacks, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
      - Page proofs, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Little Square Review #5 and #6. (Indian issue with N. H. Russell)
      - Correspondence, 1967-1972; 2 (Box 2)
      - Working proofs, 1968 (Box 2)
      - Text, 1968 (Box 2)
      - Responses, 1968-1973 (Box 2)
    - Little Square Review #7. Three Western Poets. Robert Brandts, F. R. Bresgal, Dick Strong
      - Working file, 1969 (Box 2)
      - Responses, 1969-70 (Box 2)
    - Little Square Review #8. Two Northwest Poets
      - Alexander Davies, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
      - Tom Artin, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
      - Responses, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
    - Little Square Review #9-#10
      - Proofs, etc., mss., 1972 (Box 2)
      - Correspondence, 1968-1974 (Box 2)
      - Responses, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Publicity and Advertising, 1966-1969 (Box 3)
    - Copyright Office, 1968-1972 (Box 3)
    - Exchanges, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - Inquiries, 1966-1973 (Box 3)
    - Receipts, 1966-1972; 3 (Box 3)
    - Orders, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
    - Payments, 1970 (Box 3)
    - Possible for Publication, 1968-1971 (Box 3)
    - Returns and Complaints, 1967-1973 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence
    - American Literary Anthology, 1967-1971 (Box 3)
    - Bowers, Edgar, 1964-2000 (Box 3)
    - Cunningham, J. V., 1967-1982 (Box 3)
    - Horton, Bill (Sun Press), 1967-1968 (Box 3)
    - Hitchcock, George, 1962-1970 (Box 3)
    - Ignotow, David and Rose Graublatt. Chelsea submissions and acceptances, 1960-1973 (Box 3)
    - Knoepfle, John, 1968-1987 (Box 3)
    - Lurie, Alison, 1972-1986 (Box 3)
    - Mehta, Ved, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
    - Menashtash, 1968-1971 (Box 3)
    - Meyers, Bert, 1966-1975 (Box 3)
    - Miles, Josephine, 1960-1986 (Box 3)
    - Mooney, Steve, 1966-1971 (Box 3)
    - Nims, John Frederick, 1995-1998 (Box 3)
    - Pinsky, Robert, 1974-1979 (Box 3)
    - Powers, J.F., 1974-1981 (Box 3)
    - Seth, Vikram, 1985-1995 (Box 3)
    - Stafford, William, 1971-1990 (Box 3)
    - Wallace, Robert-Light Year, 1983-1989 (Box 4)
    - West, Paul, 1970-1991 (Box 4)
  - Printed material
    - Little Square Review #1, 1966 (Box 4)
    - Little Square Review #2, 1967 (Box 4)
    - Little Square Review #3, 1967 (Box 4)
    - Little Square Review #4, 1967 (Box 4)
    - Little Square Review #5 and #6, 1968 (Box 4)
    - Little Square Review #7, 1969 (Box 4)
    - Little Square Review #8, 1970 (Box 4)
    - Little Square Review #9 and #10, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Little Square Review fliers, notes, undated (Box 4)
- April 2003 Acquisition, 1974; 2; 0.21; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 492
  - Reproduction of photograph of Ishi, inscribed on verso by William Stafford to John Ridland, 1974 December 30 (Box 5)
  - Skinner, John, Version of American Indian texts, typescripts, various drafts, undated; 5 (Box 5)
- August 2005 Acquisition, undated; 3; 0.42; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 808
  - Box of index cards containing subscription and sales information, undated (Box 6)